<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>hiver 2022 on Webinaires du département de sciences de la décision</title>
    <link>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/tags/hiver-2022/</link>
    <description>Recent content in hiver 2022 on Webinaires du département de sciences de la décision</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>fr-ca</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/tags/hiver-2022/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Toward social welfare and fairness in kidney exchange programs</title>
      <link>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/post/h2022/2022-04-28/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/post/h2022/2022-04-28/</guid>
      <description>Date: jeudi 28 avril 2022 Heure: 11h00-12h00 Salle Manuvie, bâtiment Côte-Sainte-Catherine Séminaire webdiffusé, organisé conjointement avec la Chaire de théorie des jeux et gestion
Résumé: Matching markets are part of our daily lives, appearing on online platforms, school admissions and health systems. Their study attracts the interest of optimizers and game theorists. In this talk, we will focus on a particular matching market, the kidney exchange program (KEP), where combinatorial optimization and game theory play an important role.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Comparative Probability Metrics: Using Posterior Probabilities to Account for Practical Equivalence in A/B tests</title>
      <link>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/post/h2022/2022-03-23/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/post/h2022/2022-03-23/</guid>
      <description>Date: mercredi 23 mars 2022 Heure: 15h00-16h00 Résumé: Online controlled experiments (i.e., A/B tests) have become an extremely valuable tool used by internet and technology companies for purposes of advertising, product development, product improvement, customer acquisition, and customer retention to name a few. The data-driven decisions that result from these experiments are typically informed by null hypothesis significance tests and analyses based on p-values. However, attention has recently been drawn to the shortcomings of hypothesis testing, and an emphasis has been placed on the development of new methodologies that overcome these shortcomings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Differentially private inference via noisy optimization</title>
      <link>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/post/h2022/2022-02-25/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/post/h2022/2022-02-25/</guid>
      <description>Date: vendredi 25 février 2022 Heure: 15h00-16h00 Webinaire organisé conjointement avec le département de mathématiques et de statistique de l&amp;rsquo;Université Laval
Résumé: We propose a general optimization-based framework for computing differentially private M-estimators and a new method for constructing differentially private confidence regions. Firstly, we show that robust statistics can be used in conjunction with noisy gradient descent or noisy Newton methods in order to obtain optimal private estimators with global linear or quadratic convergence, respectively.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
