<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>HEC on Webinaires du département de sciences de la décision</title>
    <link>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/categories/hec/</link>
    <description>Recent content in HEC on Webinaires du département de sciences de la décision</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>fr-ca</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/categories/hec/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Personalized Dynamic Pricing with Machine Learning: High Dimensional Features and Heterogeneous Elasticity</title>
      <link>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/post/h2023/2023-02-24/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/post/h2023/2023-02-24/</guid>
      <description>Date: vendredi 24 février 2023 Heure: 10h-11h Webinaire Zoom Résumé: We consider a seller who can dynamically adjust the price of a product at the individual customer level, by utilizing information about customers&amp;rsquo; characteristics encoded as a $d$-dimensional feature vector. We assume a personalized demand model, parameters of which depend on $s$ out of the $d$ features. The seller initially does not know the relationship between the customer features and the product demand, but learns this through sales observations over a selling horizon of $T$ periods.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stochastic Algorithms in the Large</title>
      <link>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/post/a2022/2022-12-06/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/post/a2022/2022-12-06/</guid>
      <description>Date: mardi 6 décembre 2022 Heure: 10h-11h Hybride, salle Hélène-Desmarais Résumé: In this talk, I will present a framework, inspired by random matrix theory, for analyzing the dynamics of stochastic optimization algorithms (e.g., stochastic gradient descent (SGD) and momentum (SGD + M)) when both the number of samples and dimensions are large. Using this new framework, we show that the dynamics of optimization algorithms on a least squares problem with random data become deterministic in the large sample and dimensional limit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>(Almost) all of Entity Resolution</title>
      <link>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/post/a2022/2022-11-25/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/post/a2022/2022-11-25/</guid>
      <description>Date: vendredi 25 novembre 2022 Heure: 15h30-16h30 Hybride, salle Sony Séminaire organisé conjointement avec le CRM (Statlab)
Résumé: Whether the goal is to estimate the number of people that live in a congressional district, to estimate the number of individuals that have died in an armed conflict, or to disambiguate individual authors using bibliographic data, all these applications have a common theme — integrating information from multiple sources. Before such questions can be answered, databases must be cleaned and integrated in a systematic and accurate way, commonly known as record linkage, de-duplication, or entity resolution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Optimal stopping mean-field games: a linear programming formulation and applications to entry-exit games in electricity markets</title>
      <link>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/post/a2022/2022-11-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/post/a2022/2022-11-11/</guid>
      <description>Date: vendredi 11 novembre 2022 Heure: 10h00-11h00 Zoom, webdiffusé salle Société canadienne des postes Séminaire organisé conjointement avec Quantact
Résumé: In this talk, we present recent results on the linear programming approach to stopping mean-field games in a general setting. This relaxed control approach allows to prove existence results under weak assumptions, and lends itself well to numerical implementation. We consider mean-field game problems where the representative agent chooses the optimal time to exit the game, where the instantaneous reward function and the coefficients of the state process may depend on the distribution of the other agents.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Employee Views of Leveraged Buy-Out Transactions</title>
      <link>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/post/a2022/2022-11-02/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/post/a2022/2022-11-02/</guid>
      <description>Date: mercredi 2 novembre 2022 Heure: 12h00-13h00 Hybride, salle Serge-Saucier Séminaire organisé conjointement avec Quantact et le département de finance
Résumé: This paper offers a comprehensive view of employee satisfaction: we make use of 700,000 ratings, in addition to 500,000 written reviews posted by employees of all ranks, in different industries, types of companies, and in companies that underwent different types of ownership changes. Employee satisfaction is lower following a company acquisition; more so when it is a Leveraged Buy-Out (LBO).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Computer Model Emulation Using Deep Gaussian Processes</title>
      <link>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/post/a2022/2022-10-28/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/post/a2022/2022-10-28/</guid>
      <description>Date: vendredi 28 octobre 2022 Heure: 15h30-16h30 salle Hélène-Desmarais, Côte-Sainte-Catherine Colloque organisé conjointement avec le CRM (Statlab)
Résumé: Computer models are often used to explore physical systems. Increasingly, there are cases where the model is fast, the code is not readily accessible to scientists, but a large suite of model evaluations is available. In these cases, an &amp;ldquo;emulator&amp;rdquo; is used to stand in for the computer model. This work was motivated by a simulator for the chirp mass of binary black hole mergers where no output is observed for large portions of the input space and more than 10^6 simulator evaluations are available.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Optimal and robust combination of forecasts via constrained optimization and shrinkage</title>
      <link>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/post/a2022/2022-10-14/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/post/a2022/2022-10-14/</guid>
      <description>Date: vendredi 14 octobre 2022 Heure: 15h-16h salle St-Hubert Colloque organisé conjointement avec Quantact
Résumé: We introduce various methods that combine forecasts using constrained optimization with penalty. A non-negativity constraint is imposed on the weights, and several penalties are considered, taking the form of a divergence from a reference combination scheme. In contrast with most of the existing approaches, our framework performs forecast selection and combination in one step, allowing for potentially sparse combining schemes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Leverage Effect and Propagation</title>
      <link>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/post/h2022/2022-06-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/post/h2022/2022-06-10/</guid>
      <description>Date: vendredi 10 juin 2022 Heure: 11h00-12h00 Hybride, Salle Sony et Zoom Séminaire organisé conjointement avec Quantact
Résumé: This paper proposes a new way to measure the leverage effect and its propagation over time. We also show that, with respect to the newly proposed measure, common volatility models like the GJRGARCH, the Exponential GARCH, and the asymmetric SV can be inaccurate to correctly represent the leverage effect and its propagation for financial time series.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Efficient Estimation of Bid-Ask Spreads from Open, High, Low, and Close Prices</title>
      <link>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/post/h2022/2022-05-10b/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/post/h2022/2022-05-10b/</guid>
      <description>Date: mardi 10 mai 2022 Heure: 12h00-13h00 Salle Transat Séminaire brownbag organisé conjointement avec le département de finance.
Résumé: This paper formally derives an efficient estimator of the bid-ask spread from open, high, low, and close prices. The estimator is asymptotically unbiased and optimally combines the full set of price data to minimize the estimation variance. In absence of quote data, it delivers the most accurate estimates of bid-ask spreads theoretically, numerically, and empirically.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning and reasoning with constraint solving</title>
      <link>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/post/h2022/2022-05-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/post/h2022/2022-05-10/</guid>
      <description>Date: mardi 10 mai 2022 Heure: 11h00-12h00 En ligne (Zoom) Webinaire organisé conjointement avec le GÉRAD
Résumé: Industry and society are increasingly automating processes, which requires solving constrained optimisation problems. This includes vehicle routing, demand-response planning, rostering and more. To find not just optimal solutions, but also &amp;lsquo;desirable&amp;rsquo; solution by the end user, it is increasingly important to offer tools that automatically learn from the user and the environment and that support the constraint modelling in interpretable ways.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Toward social welfare and fairness in kidney exchange programs</title>
      <link>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/post/h2022/2022-04-28/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/post/h2022/2022-04-28/</guid>
      <description>Date: jeudi 28 avril 2022 Heure: 11h00-12h00 Salle Manuvie, bâtiment Côte-Sainte-Catherine Séminaire webdiffusé, organisé conjointement avec la Chaire de théorie des jeux et gestion
Résumé: Matching markets are part of our daily lives, appearing on online platforms, school admissions and health systems. Their study attracts the interest of optimizers and game theorists. In this talk, we will focus on a particular matching market, the kidney exchange program (KEP), where combinatorial optimization and game theory play an important role.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Comparative Probability Metrics: Using Posterior Probabilities to Account for Practical Equivalence in A/B tests</title>
      <link>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/post/h2022/2022-03-23/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/post/h2022/2022-03-23/</guid>
      <description>Date: mercredi 23 mars 2022 Heure: 15h00-16h00 Résumé: Online controlled experiments (i.e., A/B tests) have become an extremely valuable tool used by internet and technology companies for purposes of advertising, product development, product improvement, customer acquisition, and customer retention to name a few. The data-driven decisions that result from these experiments are typically informed by null hypothesis significance tests and analyses based on p-values. However, attention has recently been drawn to the shortcomings of hypothesis testing, and an emphasis has been placed on the development of new methodologies that overcome these shortcomings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Differentially private inference via noisy optimization</title>
      <link>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/post/h2022/2022-02-25/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/post/h2022/2022-02-25/</guid>
      <description>Date: vendredi 25 février 2022 Heure: 15h00-16h00 Webinaire organisé conjointement avec le département de mathématiques et de statistique de l&amp;rsquo;Université Laval
Résumé: We propose a general optimization-based framework for computing differentially private M-estimators and a new method for constructing differentially private confidence regions. Firstly, we show that robust statistics can be used in conjunction with noisy gradient descent or noisy Newton methods in order to obtain optimal private estimators with global linear or quadratic convergence, respectively.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Size Distribution of Firms and Strategic Investments in Large Markets: A Stochastic Mean Field Game Approach</title>
      <link>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/post/a2021/2021-11-05/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/post/a2021/2021-11-05/</guid>
      <description>Date: vendredi 5 novembre 2021 Heure: 14h00-15h00 Résumé: This paper analyzes how firm size heterogeneity distribution affects capacity investments and profits in large competitive markets with both idiosyncratic and aggregate uncertainty shocks. We use a mean field game approach where firms&amp;rsquo; sizes are heterogeneously distributed and decisions on capacity investments (addition) or disinvestments (withdrawal) are optimally made over time to enhance prospects of earning profits under uncertainty. A mean field game framework allows for consideration of markets with a large population of interacting firms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Opinionated practices for teaching reproducibility: motivation, guided instruction and practice</title>
      <link>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/post/a2021/2021-10-29/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/post/a2021/2021-10-29/</guid>
      <description>Date: vendredi 29 octobre 2021 Heure: 15h30-16h30 Résumé: In the data science courses at the University of British Columbia, we define data science as the study, development and practice of reproducible and auditable processes to obtain insight from data. While reproducibility is core to our definition, most data science learners enter the field with other aspects of data science in mind, for example predictive modelling, which is often one of the most interesting topic to novices.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Selective inference on trees</title>
      <link>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/post/a2021/2021-10-04/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/post/a2021/2021-10-04/</guid>
      <description>Date: lundi 4 octobre 2021 Heure: 15h-16h Résumé: The ever-increasing scope and scale of data collection has shifted the focus of data collection away from testing pre-specified hypotheses and towards hypothesis generation. Researchers are often interested in performing exploratory data analysis on a data set to generate hypotheses, then to validate those hypotheses in that same data via tests of significance. Unfortunately, this type of &amp;ldquo;double-dipping&amp;rdquo; can lead to extremely inflated type I error rates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rethinking Introductory Statistics for Life Sciences Programs</title>
      <link>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/post/h2021/2021-05-18/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/post/h2021/2021-05-18/</guid>
      <description>Date: 18 mai 2021 Heure: 13h30-14h30 Résumé: Despite reproducibility concerns in science, an increased awareness of the prevalence of statistical errors in life sciences research, and even a tightening up of quantitative reporting standards in journals, statistical errors continue to permeate life sciences research. Yet, life science students often only need to take one Statistics course in their undergraduate programs, if that. What can we, as educators, do to prepare future life scientists for statistical practice in research when we have such limited time with them?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dynamic Optimization for Multi-Goals-Based Wealth Management</title>
      <link>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/post/h2021/2021-05-06/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/post/h2021/2021-05-06/</guid>
      <description>Date: 6 mai 2021 Heure: 13h30-14h30 Résumé: We develop a dynamic programming methodology that seeks to maximize investor outcomes over multiple, potentially competing goals (such as upgrading a home, paying college tuition, or maintaining an income stream in retirement), even when financial resources are limited. Unlike Monte Carlo approaches currently in wide use in the wealth management industry, our approach uses investor preferences to dynamically make the optimal determination for fulfilling or not fulfilling each goal and for selecting the investor’s investment portfolio.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>When does eco-efficiency rebound or backfire? An analytical model</title>
      <link>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/post/h2021/2021-04-07/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/post/h2021/2021-04-07/</guid>
      <description>Date: 7 avril 2021 Heure: 9h00-10h00 Résumé: It is known that an eco-efficiency strategy, which saves resources in the production process, may be offset by a rebound effect; it may even backfire. Less known are the exact conditions under which eco-efficiency rebounds or backfires. This article fills the gap by providing an analytical model of the rebound and backfire effects. We propose an optimal control framework of dynamic pricing and eco-efficiency investment, for which eco-efficiency reduces the unit production cost and boosts the demand of environmentally concerned consumers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Convex Optimization</title>
      <link>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/post/h2021/2021-03-17/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/post/h2021/2021-03-17/</guid>
      <description>Date: 17 mars 2021 Heure: 15h00-16h00 Résumé: Convex optimization has emerged as useful tool for applications that include data analysis and model fitting, resource allocation, engineering design, network design and optimization, finance, and control and signal processing. After an overview of the mathematics, algorithms, and software frameworks for convex optimization, we turn to common themes that arise across applications, such as sparsity and relaxation. We describe recent work on real-time embedded convex optimization, in which small problems are solved repeatedly in millisecond or microsecond time frames.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Joint integrative analysis of multiple data sources with correlated vector outcomes</title>
      <link>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/post/h2021/2021-02-19/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/post/h2021/2021-02-19/</guid>
      <description>Date: 19 février 2021 Heure: 15h30-16h30 Résumé: We consider the joint estimation of regression parameters from multiple potentially heterogeneous data sources with correlated vector outcomes. The primary goal of this joint integrative analysis is to estimate covariate effects on all vector outcomes through a marginal regression model in a statistically and computationally efficient way. We present a general class of distributed estimators that can be implemented in a parallelized computational scheme.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Risk-neutral moments based estimation of continuous time jump-diffusion models</title>
      <link>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/post/a2020/2020-12-04/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/post/a2020/2020-12-04/</guid>
      <description>Date: 4 décembre 2020 Heure: 15h00-16h00 Résumé: This paper provides a novel methodology for estimating option pricing models based on risk‐neutral moments. We synthesize the distribution extracted from a panel of option prices and exploit linear relationships between risk‐neutral cumulants and latent factors within the continuous time affine stochastic volatility framework. We find that fitting the Andersen et al. (Journal of Financial Economics, 2015, 117(3), 558–584) option valuation model to risk‐neutral moments captures the bulk of the information in option prices.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>High-Frequency Factor Models and Regressions</title>
      <link>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/post/a2020/2020-11-27/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/post/a2020/2020-11-27/</guid>
      <description>Date: 27 novembre 2020 Heure: 15h00-16h00 Résumé: We consider a nonparametric time series regression model. Our framework allows precise estimation of betas without the usual assumption of betas being piecewise constant. This property makes our framework particularly suitable to study individual stocks. We provide an inference framework for all components of the model, including idiosyncratic volatility and idiosyncratic jumps. Our empirical analysis investigates the largest data set in the high-frequency literature.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Developing an Open Energy Outlook for the United States Using Tools for Energy Model Optimization and Analysis (Temoa)</title>
      <link>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/post/a2020/2020-11-05/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/post/a2020/2020-11-05/</guid>
      <description>Date: 05 novembre 2020 Heure: 15h00-16h00 Résumé: Climate change coupled with rapid technological innovation is driving large scale change in the global energy system. Computer models of the energy system – referred to as energy optimization system models – provide a way to examine future energy system evolution, test the effects of proposed policy, and explore the role of future uncertainty. In this talk, I will describe Tools for Energy Model Optimization and Analysis (Temoa), an open source energy system optimization model designed to conduct rigorous uncertainty analysis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Banking networks, systemic risk, and the credit cycle in emerging markets</title>
      <link>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/post/a2020/2020-10-23/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/post/a2020/2020-10-23/</guid>
      <description>Date: 23 octobre 2020 Heure: 15h00-16h00 Résumé: We undertake a large-scale empirical examination of systemic risk among 1048 financial institutions in a large sample of 23 emerging markets, broken down into 5 regions. This work extends the large literature on systemic risk in the US, Europe, and other developed countries to emerging markets, which is relatively under-researched. We present a novel systemic risk score for each financial system by region, across time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Optimizing Post-Disruption Response Operations to Improve Resilience of Critical Infrastructure Systems</title>
      <link>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/post/a2020/2020-10-16/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/post/a2020/2020-10-16/</guid>
      <description>Date: 16 octobre 2020 Heure: 15h00 – 16h00 Résumé: Critical infrastructure systems (CIS) underpin almost every aspect of the modern society by enabling the essential functions through overlaying service networks. After a disruption impacting the CIS, the functionality of the overlaying service networks degrades. Thus, after an extreme event, in order to minimize the negative impact to society, it is crucial to restore the disrupted CIS as soon as possible. In this talk, we focus on disruptions created by natural hazards on transportation CIS and develop methods to efficiently plan the post-disaster response operations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Use of Binary Choice Forests to Model and Estimate Discrete Choices</title>
      <link>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/post/a2020/2020-10-09/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/post/a2020/2020-10-09/</guid>
      <description>Date: 9 octobre 2020 Heure: 15h00-16h00 Résumé: We show the equivalence of discrete choice models and the class of binary choice forests, which are random forests based on binary choice trees. This suggests that standard machine learning techniques based on random forests can serve to estimate discrete choice models with an interpretable output. This is confirmed by our data-driven theoretical results which show that random forests can predict the choice probability of any discrete choice model consistently, with its splitting criterion capable of recovering preference rank lists.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Machine Learning for Causal Inference</title>
      <link>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/post/a2020/2020-09-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/post/a2020/2020-09-11/</guid>
      <description>Date: 11 septembre 2020 Heure: 16h00-17h00 Résumé: Given advances in machine learning over the past decades, it is now possible to accurately solve difficult non-parametric prediction problems in a way that is routine and reproducible. In this talk, I&amp;rsquo;ll discuss how machine learning tools can be rigorously integrated into observational study analyses, and how they interact with classical statistical ideas around randomization, semiparametric modeling, double robustness, etc. I&amp;rsquo;ll also survey some recent advances in methods for treatment heterogeneity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tail risk and style dependence in the fund industry: A multivariate extreme value approach</title>
      <link>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/post/h2020/2020-03-05/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/post/h2020/2020-03-05/</guid>
      <description>Date: 5 mars 2020 Heure: 15h30-16h30 Lieu: Salle 2.825, CSC, HEC Montréal Résumé: In this paper, we study the connectedness between extreme losses of hedge funds, a crucial feature for systemic risk management. To do so, we exploit cross-sections of hedge funds monthly returns grouped by investment styles, and build a time- varying measure of tail dependence across styles. Relying on extreme value theory and regression techniques, we study the dynamics of the tail dependencies between fund styles conditional on factors reflecting the economic uncertainty and the stock market performance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Longitudinal functional regression: tests of significance</title>
      <link>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/post/h2020/2020-01-31/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/post/h2020/2020-01-31/</guid>
      <description>Date: 31 janvier 2020 Heure: 16h00-17h00 Lieu: Salle Béton-Grilli, CSC, HEC Montréal Résumé: We consider longitudinal functional regression, where, for each subject, the response consists of multiple curves observed at different time visits. We discuss tests of significance in two general settings. First, when there are no additional covariates, we develop a hypothesis testing methodology for formally assessing that the mean function does not vary over time. Second, in the presence of other covariates, we propose a testing procedure to determine the significance of the covariate&amp;rsquo;s time-varying effect formally.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some statistical applications of generative neural networks</title>
      <link>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/post/h2020/2020-01-09/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/post/h2020/2020-01-09/</guid>
      <description>Date: 9 janvier 2020 Heure: 15h30-16h30 Lieu: Salle 2.825, CSC, HEC Montréal Résumé: We present some examples of how the field of statistics can benefit from the Deep Learning movement. First, using generative neural networks (GNNs), we are now able to produce quasi Monte Carlo samples from &amp;ldquo;almost any&amp;rdquo; copula model. For example, we can do this even for mixtures of copulas with singular components. Second, using GNNs, we can now model and, most importantly, forecast multivariate time series without having to restrict ourselves to using only a few parametric copula families to describe the underlying multivariate dependence.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Life at the (grid) edge: Evaluating energy decentralization strategies in California</title>
      <link>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/post/a2019/2019-11-29/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/post/a2019/2019-11-29/</guid>
      <description>Date: 29 Novembre 2019 Heure: 14h00-15h00 Lieu: Salle Trudeau Corporation, CSC, HEC Montréal Résumé: Avoiding the worst consequences of climate change hinges on the transition to a deeply decarbonized global energy system. Recent studies suggest that the least costly and risky way in which this transition could unfold is through radical electrification that is dominated by low-carbon sources of electricity. Several visions of this future have been put forward, some of which hinge on revolutions at the grid-edge that enable smarter energy management and vehicle electrification.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Media and the stock market: Their relationship and abnormal dynamics around earnings announcements</title>
      <link>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/post/a2019/2019-10-16/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/post/a2019/2019-10-16/</guid>
      <description>Date: 16 octobre 2019 Heure: 10h30-11h30 Lieu: Salle 2.825, CSC, HEC Montréal Résumé: This paper investigates the abnormal tone dynamics of media news articles about firms near earnings announcements and how it relates to earnings results and the stock market. We document a post-earnings abnormal tone drift, suggesting inertia in the media opinion. Also, we find that negative cumulative abnormal tone at the earnings events predicts a subsequent stock price reversal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Optimizing the design of textual indices: Impression management and Sentometrics</title>
      <link>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/post/a2019/2019-10-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/post/a2019/2019-10-11/</guid>
      <description>Date: 11 octobre 2019 Heure: 10h00-11h00 Lieu: Salle Manuvie, CSC, HEC Montréal Résumé: Textual sentiment analysis requires to select relevant texts and design weighting schemes to aggregate the intra-textual, across-text and across-time polarity expressed in textual communications. The selection and weighting decisions need to be optimized for the intended use case and account for the underlying data features like impression management by the author and the non i.i.d. nature of the textual data.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
