<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Webinaires du département de sciences de la décision</title>
    <link>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Webinaires du département de sciences de la décision</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>fr-ca</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Differentially private inference via noisy optimization</title>
      <link>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/post/h2022/2022-02-25/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/post/h2022/2022-02-25/</guid>
      <description>Date: vendredi 25 février 2022 Heure: 15h00-16h00 Webinaire organisé conjointement avec le département de mathématiques et de statistique de l&amp;rsquo;Université Laval
Résumé: We propose a general optimization-based framework for computing differentially private M-estimators and a new method for constructing differentially private confidence regions. Firstly, we show that robust statistics can be used in conjunction with noisy gradient descent or noisy Newton methods in order to obtain optimal private estimators with global linear or quadratic convergence, respectively.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Size Distribution of Firms and Strategic Investments in Large Markets: A Stochastic Mean Field Game Approach</title>
      <link>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/post/a2021/2021-11-05/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/post/a2021/2021-11-05/</guid>
      <description>Date: vendredi 5 novembre 2021 Heure: 14h00-15h00 Résumé: This paper analyzes how firm size heterogeneity distribution affects capacity investments and profits in large competitive markets with both idiosyncratic and aggregate uncertainty shocks. We use a mean field game approach where firms&#39; sizes are heterogeneously distributed and decisions on capacity investments (addition) or disinvestments (withdrawal) are optimally made over time to enhance prospects of earning profits under uncertainty. A mean field game framework allows for consideration of markets with a large population of interacting firms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Opinionated practices for teaching reproducibility: motivation, guided instruction and practice</title>
      <link>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/post/a2021/2021-10-29/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/post/a2021/2021-10-29/</guid>
      <description>Date: vendredi 29 octobre 2021 Heure: 15h30-16h30 Résumé: In the data science courses at the University of British Columbia, we define data science as the study, development and practice of reproducible and auditable processes to obtain insight from data. While reproducibility is core to our definition, most data science learners enter the field with other aspects of data science in mind, for example predictive modelling, which is often one of the most interesting topic to novices.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Selective inference on trees</title>
      <link>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/post/a2021/2021-10-04/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/post/a2021/2021-10-04/</guid>
      <description>Date: lundi 4 octobre 2021 Heure: 15h-16h Résumé: The ever-increasing scope and scale of data collection has shifted the focus of data collection away from testing pre-specified hypotheses and towards hypothesis generation. Researchers are often interested in performing exploratory data analysis on a data set to generate hypotheses, then to validate those hypotheses in that same data via tests of significance. Unfortunately, this type of &amp;ldquo;double-dipping&amp;rdquo; can lead to extremely inflated type I error rates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rethinking Introductory Statistics for Life Sciences Programs</title>
      <link>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/post/h2021/2021-05-18/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/post/h2021/2021-05-18/</guid>
      <description>Date: 18 mai 2021 Heure: 13h30-14h30 Résumé: Despite reproducibility concerns in science, an increased awareness of the prevalence of statistical errors in life sciences research, and even a tightening up of quantitative reporting standards in journals, statistical errors continue to permeate life sciences research. Yet, life science students often only need to take one Statistics course in their undergraduate programs, if that. What can we, as educators, do to prepare future life scientists for statistical practice in research when we have such limited time with them?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dynamic Optimization for Multi-Goals-Based Wealth Management</title>
      <link>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/post/h2021/2021-05-06/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/post/h2021/2021-05-06/</guid>
      <description>Date: 6 mai 2021 Heure: 13h30-14h30 Résumé: We develop a dynamic programming methodology that seeks to maximize investor outcomes over multiple, potentially competing goals (such as upgrading a home, paying college tuition, or maintaining an income stream in retirement), even when financial resources are limited. Unlike Monte Carlo approaches currently in wide use in the wealth management industry, our approach uses investor preferences to dynamically make the optimal determination for fulfilling or not fulfilling each goal and for selecting the investor’s investment portfolio.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>When does eco-efficiency rebound or backfire? An analytical model</title>
      <link>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/post/h2021/2021-04-07/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/post/h2021/2021-04-07/</guid>
      <description>Date: 7 avril 2021 Heure: 9h00-10h00 Résumé: It is known that an eco-efficiency strategy, which saves resources in the production process, may be offset by a rebound effect; it may even backfire. Less known are the exact conditions under which eco-efficiency rebounds or backfires. This article fills the gap by providing an analytical model of the rebound and backfire effects. We propose an optimal control framework of dynamic pricing and eco-efficiency investment, for which eco-efficiency reduces the unit production cost and boosts the demand of environmentally concerned consumers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Convex Optimization</title>
      <link>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/post/h2021/2021-03-17/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/post/h2021/2021-03-17/</guid>
      <description>Date: 17 mars 2021 Heure: 15h00-16h00 Résumé: Convex optimization has emerged as useful tool for applications that include data analysis and model fitting, resource allocation, engineering design, network design and optimization, finance, and control and signal processing. After an overview of the mathematics, algorithms, and software frameworks for convex optimization, we turn to common themes that arise across applications, such as sparsity and relaxation. We describe recent work on real-time embedded convex optimization, in which small problems are solved repeatedly in millisecond or microsecond time frames.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nonparametric Tests for Informative Selection in Complex Surveys</title>
      <link>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/post/h2021/crm-2021-03-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/post/h2021/crm-2021-03-12/</guid>
      <description>Date: 12 mars 2021 Heure: 15h30-16h30 Résumé: Informative selection, in which the distribution of response variables given that they are sampled is different from their distribution in the population, is pervasive in complex surveys. Failing to take such informativeness into account can produce severe inferential errors, including biased and inconsistent estimation of population parameters. While several parametric procedures exist to test for informative selection, these methods are limited in scope and their parametric assumptions are difficult to assess.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Joint integrative analysis of multiple data sources with correlated vector outcomes</title>
      <link>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/post/h2021/2021-02-19/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/post/h2021/2021-02-19/</guid>
      <description>Date: 19 février 2021 Heure: 15h30-16h30 Résumé: We consider the joint estimation of regression parameters from multiple potentially heterogeneous data sources with correlated vector outcomes. The primary goal of this joint integrative analysis is to estimate covariate effects on all vector outcomes through a marginal regression model in a statistically and computationally efficient way. We present a general class of distributed estimators that can be implemented in a parallelized computational scheme.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spatio-temporal methods for estimating subsurface ocean thermal response to tropical cyclones</title>
      <link>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/post/h2021/crm-2021-02-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/post/h2021/crm-2021-02-12/</guid>
      <description>Date: 12 février 2021 Heure: 15h30-16h30 Résumé: Tropical cyclones (TCs), driven by heat exchange between the air and sea, pose a substantial risk to many communities around the world. Accurate characterization of the subsurface ocean thermal response to TC passage is crucial for accurate TC intensity forecasts and for understanding the role TCs play in the global climate system, yet that characterization is complicated by the high-noise ocean environment, correlations inherent in spatio-temporal data, relative scarcity of in situ observations and the entanglement of the TC-induced signal with seasonal signals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Small Area Estimation in Low- and Middle-Income Countries </title>
      <link>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/post/h2021/crm-2021-01-29/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/post/h2021/crm-2021-01-29/</guid>
      <description>Date: 29 janvier 2021 Heure: 15h30-16h30 Résumé: The under-five mortality rate (U5MR) is a key barometer of the health of a nation. Unfortunately, many people living in low- and middle-income countries are not covered by civil registration systems. This makes estimation of the U5MR, particularly at the subnational level, difficult. In this talk, I will describe models that have been developed to produce the official United Nations (UN) subnational U5MR estimates in 22 countries.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Asymptotic Expansion Formulas for Diffusion Processes Based on the Perturbation Method</title>
      <link>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/post/h2021/2021-01-22/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/post/h2021/2021-01-22/</guid>
      <description>Date: 22 janvier 2021 Heure: 11h00-12h00 Résumé: Diffusion processes are a class of models that plays a prominent role in describing the time-continuous evolution of phenomena in the natural and social sciences. However, only in very few cases the stochastic differential equation driving the process can be analytically solved. Based on the perturbation method, we present asymptotic expansion formulas to generate accurate approximations to the solution of arbitrary diffusions. In particular, we expand the characteristic function of the process.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quasi-score driven models</title>
      <link>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/post/a2020/quantact-2020-12-04/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/post/a2020/quantact-2020-12-04/</guid>
      <description>Date: 4 décembre 2020 Heure: 10h00-11h00 Résumé: This paper introduces a new class of observation-driven models, including score models as a special case. This new class inherits and extends the basic ideas behind the development of score models and addresses a number of unsolved issues in the score literature. In particular, the new class of models (i) allows QML estimation of static parameters, (ii) keeps the downweighting mechanism of the GAS models but allows the updating equation of the conditional moments to be disconnected from the density of the innovations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Risk-neutral moments based estimation of continuous time jump-diffusion models</title>
      <link>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/post/a2020/2020-12-04/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/post/a2020/2020-12-04/</guid>
      <description>Date: 4 décembre 2020 Heure: 15h00-16h00 Résumé: This paper provides a novel methodology for estimating option pricing models based on risk‐neutral moments. We synthesize the distribution extracted from a panel of option prices and exploit linear relationships between risk‐neutral cumulants and latent factors within the continuous time affine stochastic volatility framework. We find that fitting the Andersen et al. (Journal of Financial Economics, 2015, 117(3), 558–584) option valuation model to risk‐neutral moments captures the bulk of the information in option prices.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>High-Frequency Factor Models and Regressions</title>
      <link>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/post/a2020/2020-11-27/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/post/a2020/2020-11-27/</guid>
      <description>Date: 27 novembre 2020 Heure: 15h00-16h00 Résumé: We consider a nonparametric time series regression model. Our framework allows precise estimation of betas without the usual assumption of betas being piecewise constant. This property makes our framework particularly suitable to study individual stocks. We provide an inference framework for all components of the model, including idiosyncratic volatility and idiosyncratic jumps. Our empirical analysis investigates the largest data set in the high-frequency literature.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Climate change concerns and the performance of green versus brown stocks</title>
      <link>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/post/a2020/quantact-2020-11-20/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/post/a2020/quantact-2020-11-20/</guid>
      <description>Date: 20 novembre 2020 Heure: 14h00-15h00 Résumé: We empirically test the prediction of Pastor, Stambaugh, and Taylor (2020) that green firms can outperform brown firms when climate change concerns strengthen unexpectedly for S&amp;amp;P 500 companies over the period January 2010 - June 2018. To capture unexpected increases in climate change concerns, we construct a Media Climate Change Concern index using climate change-related news published by major U.S. newspapers. We find a negative relationship between the firms’ exposure to the Media Climate Change Concerns index and the level of the firm’s greenhouse gas emission per unit of revenue.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Approximate Cross-Validation for Large Data and High Dimensions</title>
      <link>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/post/a2020/crm-2020-11-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/post/a2020/crm-2020-11-13/</guid>
      <description>Date: 13 novembre 2020 Heure: 15h30-16h30 Résumé: The error or variability of statistical and machine learning algorithms is often assessed by repeatedly re-fitting a model with different weighted versions of the observed data. The ubiquitous tools of cross-validation (CV) and the bootstrap are examples of this technique. These methods are powerful in large part due to their model agnosticism but can be slow to run on modern, large data sets due to the need to repeatedly re-fit the model.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Developing an Open Energy Outlook for the United States Using Tools for Energy Model Optimization and Analysis (Temoa)</title>
      <link>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/post/a2020/2020-11-05/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/post/a2020/2020-11-05/</guid>
      <description>Date: 05 novembre 2020 Heure: 15h00-16h00 Résumé: Climate change coupled with rapid technological innovation is driving large scale change in the global energy system. Computer models of the energy system – referred to as energy optimization system models – provide a way to examine future energy system evolution, test the effects of proposed policy, and explore the role of future uncertainty. In this talk, I will describe Tools for Energy Model Optimization and Analysis (Temoa), an open source energy system optimization model designed to conduct rigorous uncertainty analysis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Banking networks, systemic risk, and the credit cycle in emerging markets</title>
      <link>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/post/a2020/2020-10-23/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/post/a2020/2020-10-23/</guid>
      <description>Date: 23 octobre 2020 Heure: 15h00-16h00 Résumé: We undertake a large-scale empirical examination of systemic risk among 1048 financial institutions in a large sample of 23 emerging markets, broken down into 5 regions. This work extends the large literature on systemic risk in the US, Europe, and other developed countries to emerging markets, which is relatively under-researched. We present a novel systemic risk score for each financial system by region, across time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Optimizing Post-Disruption Response Operations to Improve Resilience of Critical Infrastructure Systems</title>
      <link>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/post/a2020/2020-10-16/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/post/a2020/2020-10-16/</guid>
      <description>Date: 16 octobre 2020 Heure: 15h00 – 16h00 Résumé: Critical infrastructure systems (CIS) underpin almost every aspect of the modern society by enabling the essential functions through overlaying service networks. After a disruption impacting the CIS, the functionality of the overlaying service networks degrades. Thus, after an extreme event, in order to minimize the negative impact to society, it is crucial to restore the disrupted CIS as soon as possible. In this talk, we focus on disruptions created by natural hazards on transportation CIS and develop methods to efficiently plan the post-disaster response operations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Use of Binary Choice Forests to Model and Estimate Discrete Choices</title>
      <link>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/post/a2020/2020-10-09/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/post/a2020/2020-10-09/</guid>
      <description>Date: 9 octobre 2020 Heure: 15h00-16h00 Résumé: We show the equivalence of discrete choice models and the class of binary choice forests, which are random forests based on binary choice trees. This suggests that standard machine learning techniques based on random forests can serve to estimate discrete choice models with an interpretable output. This is confirmed by our data-driven theoretical results which show that random forests can predict the choice probability of any discrete choice model consistently, with its splitting criterion capable of recovering preference rank lists.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Science, Classification, Clustering and Three-Way Data</title>
      <link>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/post/a2020/crm-2020-10-02/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/post/a2020/crm-2020-10-02/</guid>
      <description>Date: 2 octobre 2020 Heure: 15h30-16h30 Résumé: Data science is discussed along with some historical perspective. Selected problems in classification are considered, either via specific datasets or general problem types. In each case, the problem is introduced before one or more potential solutions are discussed and applied. The problems discussed include data with outliers, longitudinal data, and three-way data. The proposed approaches are generally mixture model-based.
Biographie du conférencier: Paul McNicholas is a Professor and University Scholar in the Department of Mathematics and Statistics at McMaster University.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Machine Learning for Causal Inference</title>
      <link>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/post/a2020/2020-09-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/post/a2020/2020-09-11/</guid>
      <description>Date: 11 septembre 2020 Heure: 16h00-17h00 Résumé: Given advances in machine learning over the past decades, it is now possible to accurately solve difficult non-parametric prediction problems in a way that is routine and reproducible. In this talk, I&amp;rsquo;ll discuss how machine learning tools can be rigorously integrated into observational study analyses, and how they interact with classical statistical ideas around randomization, semiparametric modeling, double robustness, etc. I&amp;rsquo;ll also survey some recent advances in methods for treatment heterogeneity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tail risk and style dependence in the fund industry: A multivariate extreme value approach</title>
      <link>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/post/h2020/2020-03-05/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/post/h2020/2020-03-05/</guid>
      <description>Date: 5 mars 2020 Heure: 15h30-16h30 Lieu: Salle 2.825, CSC, HEC Montréal Résumé: In this paper, we study the connectedness between extreme losses of hedge funds, a crucial feature for systemic risk management. To do so, we exploit cross-sections of hedge funds monthly returns grouped by investment styles, and build a time- varying measure of tail dependence across styles. Relying on extreme value theory and regression techniques, we study the dynamics of the tail dependencies between fund styles conditional on factors reflecting the economic uncertainty and the stock market performance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Longitudinal functional regression: tests of significance</title>
      <link>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/post/h2020/2020-01-31/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/post/h2020/2020-01-31/</guid>
      <description>Date: 31 janvier 2020 Heure: 16h00-17h00 Lieu: Salle Béton-Grilli, CSC, HEC Montréal Résumé: We consider longitudinal functional regression, where, for each subject, the response consists of multiple curves observed at different time visits. We discuss tests of significance in two general settings. First, when there are no additional covariates, we develop a hypothesis testing methodology for formally assessing that the mean function does not vary over time. Second, in the presence of other covariates, we propose a testing procedure to determine the significance of the covariate&amp;rsquo;s time-varying effect formally.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some statistical applications of generative neural networks</title>
      <link>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/post/h2020/2020-01-09/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/post/h2020/2020-01-09/</guid>
      <description>Date: 9 janvier 2020 Heure: 15h30-16h30 Lieu: Salle 2.825, CSC, HEC Montréal Résumé: We present some examples of how the field of statistics can benefit from the Deep Learning movement. First, using generative neural networks (GNNs), we are now able to produce quasi Monte Carlo samples from &amp;ldquo;almost any&amp;rdquo; copula model. For example, we can do this even for mixtures of copulas with singular components. Second, using GNNs, we can now model and, most importantly, forecast multivariate time series without having to restrict ourselves to using only a few parametric copula families to describe the underlying multivariate dependence.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Life at the (grid) edge: Evaluating energy decentralization strategies in California</title>
      <link>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/post/a2019/2019-11-29/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/post/a2019/2019-11-29/</guid>
      <description>Date: 29 Novembre 2019 Heure: 14h00-15h00 Lieu: Salle Trudeau Corporation, CSC, HEC Montréal Résumé: Avoiding the worst consequences of climate change hinges on the transition to a deeply decarbonized global energy system. Recent studies suggest that the least costly and risky way in which this transition could unfold is through radical electrification that is dominated by low-carbon sources of electricity. Several visions of this future have been put forward, some of which hinge on revolutions at the grid-edge that enable smarter energy management and vehicle electrification.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>General Bayesian modeling</title>
      <link>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/post/a2019/2019-11-01crm/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/post/a2019/2019-11-01crm/</guid>
      <description>Date: 4 octobre 2019 Heure: 16h00-17h00 Lieu: Burnside Hall 1104, McGill University Résumé: The work is motivated by the inflexibility of Bayesian modeling; in that only parameters of probability models are required to be connected with data. The idea is to generalize this by allowing arbitrary unknowns to be connected with data via loss functions. An updating process is then detailed which can be viewed as arising in at least a couple of ways - one being purely axiomatically driven.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Media and the stock market: Their relationship and abnormal dynamics around earnings announcements</title>
      <link>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/post/a2019/2019-10-16/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/post/a2019/2019-10-16/</guid>
      <description>Date: 16 octobre 2019 Heure: 10h30-11h30 Lieu: Salle 2.825, CSC, HEC Montréal Résumé: This paper investigates the abnormal tone dynamics of media news articles about firms near earnings announcements and how it relates to earnings results and the stock market. We document a post-earnings abnormal tone drift, suggesting inertia in the media opinion. Also, we find that negative cumulative abnormal tone at the earnings events predicts a subsequent stock price reversal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Optimizing the design of textual indices: Impression management and Sentometrics</title>
      <link>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/post/a2019/2019-10-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/post/a2019/2019-10-11/</guid>
      <description>Date: 11 octobre 2019 Heure: 10h00-11h00 Lieu: Salle Manuvie, CSC, HEC Montréal Résumé: Textual sentiment analysis requires to select relevant texts and design weighting schemes to aggregate the intra-textual, across-text and across-time polarity expressed in textual communications. The selection and weighting decisions need to be optimized for the intended use case and account for the underlying data features like impression management by the author and the non i.i.d. nature of the textual data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tales of tails, tiles and ties in dependence modeling</title>
      <link>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/post/a2019/2019-10-04crm/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/post/a2019/2019-10-04crm/</guid>
      <description>Date: 4 octobre 2019 Heure: 16h00-17h00 Lieu: Salle 1355, Pavillon André-Aisenstadt, Université de Montréal, Résumé: Modeling dependence between random variables is omnipresent in statistics. When rare events with high impact are involved, such as severe storms, floods or heat waves, the issue is both of great importance for risk management and theoretically challenging. Combining extreme-value theory with copula modeling and rank-based inference yields a particularly flexible and promising approach to this problem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Optimal picking policies for e-commerce warehouses</title>
      <link>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/post/a2019/2019-09-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/post/a2019/2019-09-10/</guid>
      <description>Date: 10 septembre 2019 Heure: 10h30-12h00 Lieu: Salle 4488, Pavillon André-Aisenstadt, Université de Montréal Résumé: In e-commerce warehouses, online retailers increase their efficiency by using a mixed-shelves (or scattered storage) concept, where unit loads are purposefully broken down into single items, which are individually stored in multiple locations. Irrespective of the stock keeping units a customer jointly orders, this storage strategy increases the likelihood that somewhere in the warehouse the items of the requested stock keeping units will be in close vicinity, which may significantly reduce an order picker&amp;rsquo;s unproductive walking time.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
