<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>hiver 2021 on Séminaires du département de sciences de la décision</title>
    <link>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/tags/hiver-2021/</link>
    <description>Recent content in hiver 2021 on Séminaires du département de sciences de la décision</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>fr-ca</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/tags/hiver-2021/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Rethinking Introductory Statistics for Life Sciences Programs</title>
      <link>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/post/h2021/2021-05-18/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/post/h2021/2021-05-18/</guid>
      <description>Date: 18 mai 2021 Heure: 13h30-14h30 Résumé: Despite reproducibility concerns in science, an increased awareness of the prevalence of statistical errors in life sciences research, and even a tightening up of quantitative reporting standards in journals, statistical errors continue to permeate life sciences research. Yet, life science students often only need to take one Statistics course in their undergraduate programs, if that. What can we, as educators, do to prepare future life scientists for statistical practice in research when we have such limited time with them?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dynamic Optimization for Multi-Goals-Based Wealth Management</title>
      <link>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/post/h2021/2021-05-06/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/post/h2021/2021-05-06/</guid>
      <description>Date: 6 mai 2021 Heure: 13h30-14h30 Résumé: We develop a dynamic programming methodology that seeks to maximize investor outcomes over multiple, potentially competing goals (such as upgrading a home, paying college tuition, or maintaining an income stream in retirement), even when financial resources are limited. Unlike Monte Carlo approaches currently in wide use in the wealth management industry, our approach uses investor preferences to dynamically make the optimal determination for fulfilling or not fulfilling each goal and for selecting the investor’s investment portfolio.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>When does eco-efficiency rebound or backfire? An analytical model</title>
      <link>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/post/h2021/2021-04-07/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/post/h2021/2021-04-07/</guid>
      <description>Date: 7 avril 2021 Heure: 9h00-10h00 Résumé: It is known that an eco-efficiency strategy, which saves resources in the production process, may be offset by a rebound effect; it may even backfire. Less known are the exact conditions under which eco-efficiency rebounds or backfires. This article fills the gap by providing an analytical model of the rebound and backfire effects. We propose an optimal control framework of dynamic pricing and eco-efficiency investment, for which eco-efficiency reduces the unit production cost and boosts the demand of environmentally concerned consumers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Convex Optimization</title>
      <link>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/post/h2021/2021-03-17/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/post/h2021/2021-03-17/</guid>
      <description>Date: 17 mars 2021 Heure: 15h00-16h00 Résumé: Convex optimization has emerged as useful tool for applications that include data analysis and model fitting, resource allocation, engineering design, network design and optimization, finance, and control and signal processing. After an overview of the mathematics, algorithms, and software frameworks for convex optimization, we turn to common themes that arise across applications, such as sparsity and relaxation. We describe recent work on real-time embedded convex optimization, in which small problems are solved repeatedly in millisecond or microsecond time frames.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nonparametric Tests for Informative Selection in Complex Surveys</title>
      <link>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/post/h2021/crm-2021-03-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/post/h2021/crm-2021-03-12/</guid>
      <description>Date: 12 mars 2021 Heure: 15h30-16h30 Résumé: Informative selection, in which the distribution of response variables given that they are sampled is different from their distribution in the population, is pervasive in complex surveys. Failing to take such informativeness into account can produce severe inferential errors, including biased and inconsistent estimation of population parameters. While several parametric procedures exist to test for informative selection, these methods are limited in scope and their parametric assumptions are difficult to assess.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Joint integrative analysis of multiple data sources with correlated vector outcomes</title>
      <link>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/post/h2021/2021-02-19/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/post/h2021/2021-02-19/</guid>
      <description>Date: 19 février 2021 Heure: 15h30-16h30 Résumé: We consider the joint estimation of regression parameters from multiple potentially heterogeneous data sources with correlated vector outcomes. The primary goal of this joint integrative analysis is to estimate covariate effects on all vector outcomes through a marginal regression model in a statistically and computationally efficient way. We present a general class of distributed estimators that can be implemented in a parallelized computational scheme.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spatio-temporal methods for estimating subsurface ocean thermal response to tropical cyclones</title>
      <link>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/post/h2021/crm-2021-02-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/post/h2021/crm-2021-02-12/</guid>
      <description>Date: 12 février 2021 Heure: 15h30-16h30 Résumé: Tropical cyclones (TCs), driven by heat exchange between the air and sea, pose a substantial risk to many communities around the world. Accurate characterization of the subsurface ocean thermal response to TC passage is crucial for accurate TC intensity forecasts and for understanding the role TCs play in the global climate system, yet that characterization is complicated by the high-noise ocean environment, correlations inherent in spatio-temporal data, relative scarcity of in situ observations and the entanglement of the TC-induced signal with seasonal signals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Small Area Estimation in Low- and Middle-Income Countries </title>
      <link>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/post/h2021/crm-2021-01-29/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/post/h2021/crm-2021-01-29/</guid>
      <description>Date: 29 janvier 2021 Heure: 15h30-16h30 Résumé: The under-five mortality rate (U5MR) is a key barometer of the health of a nation. Unfortunately, many people living in low- and middle-income countries are not covered by civil registration systems. This makes estimation of the U5MR, particularly at the subnational level, difficult. In this talk, I will describe models that have been developed to produce the official United Nations (UN) subnational U5MR estimates in 22 countries.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Asymptotic Expansion Formulas for Diffusion Processes Based on the Perturbation Method</title>
      <link>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/post/h2021/2021-01-22/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/post/h2021/2021-01-22/</guid>
      <description>Date: 22 janvier 2021 Heure: 11h00-12h00 Résumé: Diffusion processes are a class of models that plays a prominent role in describing the time-continuous evolution of phenomena in the natural and social sciences. However, only in very few cases the stochastic differential equation driving the process can be analytically solved. Based on the perturbation method, we present asymptotic expansion formulas to generate accurate approximations to the solution of arbitrary diffusions. In particular, we expand the characteristic function of the process.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
