<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>automne 2022 on Webinaires du département de sciences de la décision</title>
    <link>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/tags/automne-2022/</link>
    <description>Recent content in automne 2022 on Webinaires du département de sciences de la décision</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>fr-ca</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/tags/automne-2022/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Stochastic Algorithms in the Large</title>
      <link>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/post/a2022/2022-12-06/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/post/a2022/2022-12-06/</guid>
      <description>Date: mardi 6 décembre 2022 Heure: 10h-11h Hybride, salle Hélène-Desmarais Résumé: In this talk, I will present a framework, inspired by random matrix theory, for analyzing the dynamics of stochastic optimization algorithms (e.g., stochastic gradient descent (SGD) and momentum (SGD + M)) when both the number of samples and dimensions are large. Using this new framework, we show that the dynamics of optimization algorithms on a least squares problem with random data become deterministic in the large sample and dimensional limit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>(Almost) all of Entity Resolution</title>
      <link>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/post/a2022/2022-11-25/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/post/a2022/2022-11-25/</guid>
      <description>Date: vendredi 25 novembre 2022 Heure: 15h30-16h30 Hybride, salle Sony Séminaire organisé conjointement avec le CRM (Statlab)
Résumé: Whether the goal is to estimate the number of people that live in a congressional district, to estimate the number of individuals that have died in an armed conflict, or to disambiguate individual authors using bibliographic data, all these applications have a common theme — integrating information from multiple sources. Before such questions can be answered, databases must be cleaned and integrated in a systematic and accurate way, commonly known as record linkage, de-duplication, or entity resolution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Employee Views of Leveraged Buy-Out Transactions</title>
      <link>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/post/a2022/2022-11-02/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/post/a2022/2022-11-02/</guid>
      <description>Date: mercredi 2 novembre 2022 Heure: 12h00-13h00 Hybride, salle Serge-Saucier Séminaire organisé conjointement avec Quantact et le département de finance
Résumé: This paper offers a comprehensive view of employee satisfaction: we make use of 700,000 ratings, in addition to 500,000 written reviews posted by employees of all ranks, in different industries, types of companies, and in companies that underwent different types of ownership changes. Employee satisfaction is lower following a company acquisition; more so when it is a Leveraged Buy-Out (LBO).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Computer Model Emulation Using Deep Gaussian Processes</title>
      <link>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/post/a2022/2022-10-28/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/post/a2022/2022-10-28/</guid>
      <description>Date: vendredi 28 octobre 2022 Heure: 15h30-16h30 salle Hélène-Desmarais, Côte-Sainte-Catherine Colloque organisé conjointement avec le CRM (Statlab)
Résumé: Computer models are often used to explore physical systems. Increasingly, there are cases where the model is fast, the code is not readily accessible to scientists, but a large suite of model evaluations is available. In these cases, an &amp;ldquo;emulator&amp;rdquo; is used to stand in for the computer model. This work was motivated by a simulator for the chirp mass of binary black hole mergers where no output is observed for large portions of the input space and more than 10^6 simulator evaluations are available.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Optimal and robust combination of forecasts via constrained optimization and shrinkage</title>
      <link>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/post/a2022/2022-10-14/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://HECSciencesDecision.github.io/post/a2022/2022-10-14/</guid>
      <description>Date: vendredi 14 octobre 2022 Heure: 15h-16h salle St-Hubert Colloque organisé conjointement avec Quantact
Résumé: We introduce various methods that combine forecasts using constrained optimization with penalty. A non-negativity constraint is imposed on the weights, and several penalties are considered, taking the form of a divergence from a reference combination scheme. In contrast with most of the existing approaches, our framework performs forecast selection and combination in one step, allowing for potentially sparse combining schemes.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
